[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 39]
Indeed.
This is much more interesting.
Lai Luozhi.
In the imperial court,
you dare to act recklessly,
showing utter disregard for the law.
You're unworthy of being a subject.
If the emperor doesn't act,
the realm will be in turmoil.
Lord Lai
serves the country wholeheartedly.
If injustice prevails,
we won't accept it.
It would be ungrateful and disloyal.
You treacherous rebels!
How dare you spout such nonsense!
A hen crowing like a rooster,
that's the real disaster for Cang State.
Well, well.
you've all come out now.
Then I'd like to see
just who exactly
is this disaster for Cang State.
Guards!
Why don't you let me try?
Take a look.
This is our Cang State's
Qianniu Guard.
I've long heard
that the Imperial Security Bureau and the Imperial Investigation Department
are in cahoots,
but I never expected
that the Qianniu Guard would also side with the Lai faction.
Your Majesty have been ill for a long time,
perhaps you're become confused.
What should be said,
what should be done,
I suppose I'll have to remind you.
Do Your Majesty truly have nothing
to say to the ministers?
Lai Luozhi,
how dare you surround the palace with troops,
intending to rebel?
The Mandate of Heaven has shifted,
it is truly where the people's hearts lie.
Lai Luozhi,
you're insolent!
I didn't expect
Your Majesty would actually
fight to the death.
What a pity.
It didn't have to be this way.
Now that it's come to this,
you know
how to write
the abdication edict, don't you?
Absurd!
What qualifications do you have
to inherit the unified throne?
What if I do have such qualifications?
One should receive the Mandate of Heaven,
and establish the supreme authority.
Such wild ambition!
Your intentions are punishable by death.
So noisy.
Take these pedantic fools
and drag them out.
Cut out their tongues.
Shen Du,
why aren't you acting?
You want to sit on this throne,
but you're not qualified yet.
The Imperial Guards!
I am Shen Du of the Imperial Security Bureau.
I have thoroughly investigated the Imperial Guards
and purged the traitors among them.
Today, I lead troops to protect the sacred,
only to capture the rebels.
Dozens of lives from the Shen family
were unjustly taken.
Don't you want
to avenge them?
Think about your father, Shen Bingzhu.
Don't you want to clear his name?
I will uncover the truth myself
and seek justice for the Shen family.
You are unworthy to
stand with me.
So,
according to your speculation,
the Fire Moth Sect has been
quietly nurtured and grown over the years
because someone in the court has been assisting them.
This person
is most likely to be Lai Luozhi?
Although there's no concrete evidence,
various signs indicate that
Lai Luozhi is
inextricably linked to this matter.
The Fire Moth Sect covets power in the court,
attempting to gain leverage over
Princess Yong'an and others.
They're instigating conflicts within the royal family,
which shows that the person behind this
has deep-seated intentions
and even greater ambitions.
They even dare to meddle with the cinnabar
controlled by the court.
We can be certain that your speculation
is most likely correct.
What do you think?
The enemy is hidden.
We might as well go with the flow
and pay a man back in his own coin.
Pay a man back in his own coin.
Good.
I want to see
how effective your trap
will be.
Your Majesty.
Shen Du
specially got this spiritual medicine
from the Jinwu Tribe.
It was secretly sent into the palace.
They say it's exactly for this condition.
After drinking it,
you'll recover in half a month.
What a clever move of hiding your true intentions.
You pretended to surrender,
and you even went so far as to use yourself
and those around you as a gamble.
Rather than saying I pretended to deceive you,
it's more accurate to say your arrogance
led you to fall into
a trap that was set long ago.
There's no point in saying more.
It's still uncertain who will come out on top.
The fire moths rise,
revealing all living beings!
These envoys are fake.
I have never fully trusted you either.
Now, the commanders of the six garrison troops
are all loyal to me.
Just now,
they have surrounded the palace with their troops.
What do you have to fight against me?
The tide has turned now.
It's too late
for regrets!
Shen Du.
You could have been my
founding hero.
What a pity.
Leave no one alive.
Kill them all.
Everything will be fine.
I will protect you.
You will definitely ascend
to the throne.
You certainly will.
I won't let you die in vain.
General Zhenyuan's
troops moved swiftly,
quelling the rebellion in time.
As expected of our Cang State's
top general guarding the border.
Your Highness,
the troops of the Six Garrisons
have secretly sided with Lai Luozhi.
The deployable forces within the city
may not be enough to resist.
Currently, all prefectures
are being monitored
by the people of Fire Moth Sect.
Only one person can break up this situation.
To avoid alerting the enemy,
I humbly request Your Highness's personal assistance
to lift the siege of Xiang'an
and quell the rebellion in Cang State.
Thanks to Your Highness personally sending a secret letter
to convey the imperial will.
I never imagined there would be someone in the court
who dared to collude with the enemy,
attempting to create chaos at the border
to trap me.
[General Zhenyuan]
He would never have expected
that an elite team
had already departed for Xiang'an.
Lai Luozhi deceives people's hearts,
but he never considered
that everyone in this hall
is my closest confidant.
Now, His Majesty
is even my own nephew.
As citizens of Cang State,
at this moment,
we must stand with our country and our people.
My Fire Moth Sect disciples are countless.
Within Cang State,
the various branches of the Fire Moth Sect
rose up in rebellion with me today;
how do you plan to defeat us?
Do you intend to make all the citizens of Xiang'an City
die along with you?
Grand Commander.
The rebels outside the palace have been completely eliminated.
Lai Luozhi,
surrender now.
Just moments ago,
all of your Fire Moth Sect forces deployed across the country
have been wiped out.
The tide that was in your favor
has turned.
On the day of the Grand Court Assembly,
Lai Luozhi would surely
concentrate his forces at the imperial palace.
Jiang Langxing would deliver the message
to the constables in various regions.
At that time,
it would be the moment to eliminate
all Fire Moth Sect strongholds across the country.
Attention, all constables!
Clear out all the strongholds of the Fire Moth Sect
in the outer counties.
Capture all the cult members.
Don't let a single one escape.
Yes, sir.
[North Gate]
Liang,
if the new crossbow you designed
is successfully manufactured,
capable of firing multiple arrows at once,
it would be invincible.
It would allow our army to fight ten to one.
Then, just one elite squad
could defeat a larger force.
The weapons from the Liang family are truly marvelous.
In quelling this rebellion,
the Liang family's contribution is indispensable.
It's all thanks to Shen's unwavering support
and encouragement.
[North Gate]
You insects,
pretending to be righteous,
allowing Her Majesty to monopolize power,
incompetent and tyrannical.
Who is the culprit poisoning the foundation
of our Cang State?
It's her,
Zhou Xu!
Lai Luozhi,
you established the Fire Moth Sect,
deceiving people with tricks,
harming the loyal and good.
The number of people you've harmed is countless.
What right do you have
to speak so shamelessly here?
The reason my Fire Moth Sect can be
omnipresent in Cang State
is because I gave people
the creation of
a beautiful dream of resurrection.
As humans,
who can escape birth, aging, sickness, and death?
Who can avoid
the pain of losing their loved ones?
Not to mention ordinary people,
even those high-ranking officials and nobles,
what of it?
Mo Qianzhi also believes in me,
acting under my control.
You shameless scoundrel!
I despise people like you,
who are full of talk about benevolence and morality,
and think so highly of themselves.
You're attempting to overthrow the foundation of our country.
How could I possibly side with such treachery?
If my father were alive,
he would never allow this either.
I, Shen Du, am first and foremost a citizen of Cang State,
and only then a son of the Shen family.
Your father is a fool too.
I only want to remain true to my conscience
and the common people.
How could I possibly
collude with the likes of you?
He thinks he's upright and incorruptible,
but he's already made countless enemies.
Those who want to see him dead
are numerous.
You,
you're just as foolish as your father.
I only used a few small tricks,
and I can make your Shen family
fall into ruin.
Harming the loyal and good,
you've gone mad with cruelty.
Your delusions of power
are intolerable even to Heaven's will.
Heaven's will?
Then let me ask you,
who determined the Shen family's guilt?
Who is truly responsible for the destruction
of the Shen family?
Zhou Xu,
you're manipulating this young mute emperor
to control the government.
Have you ever woken up in the middle of the night,
feeling guilty towards the late emperor,
my royal father?
I am the true chosen one,
possessing the most supreme bloodline.
Today,
I shall rectify the wrongs
for the Xiao dynasty.
The late emperor...
Could he be...
I am the son
of the late emperor's Consort Shu.
The phoenix leads nine chicks.
Peace reigns under heaven.
Rectify the root and clarify the source.
Reestablish the universe.
Could it be that
the state preceptor's prophecy
really has a second half?
This statement is incorrect.
I'm Yan Xing, the Director in the Ministry of Justice.
Greetings,
Your Majesties.
Please rise.
Reporting to Your Majesty,
the state preceptor's prophecy indeed has a second half,
which I didn't have the chance to present earlier.
It's certainly not what Lai Luozhi just claimed.
What evidence do you have?
The true prophecy
is hidden within this undergarment.
The sun sets in the clear sky.
Calamity will come in return.
That's right.
The state preceptor made a prophecy that day.
The latter half
refers hidden ambitious schemes
among the court officials.
It intended to remind Your Majesty
to be wary of those around you.
Lai Luozhi has painstakingly managed
the Fire Moth Sect for many years.
The cultists have been secretly causing trouble.
The state preceptor noticed something amiss,
and because of this,
he became suspicious
of Lai Luozhi's identity.
Lacking evidence,
[The sun sets in the clear sky.]
the state preceptor had no choice but to convey his suspicions
[The sun sets in the clear sky. Calamity will come in return.]
to the world through a prophecy.
[The sun sets in the clear sky.]
Perhaps realizing that his movements
were being secretly monitored by Lai Luozhi,
he had to embroider the prophecy
on a piece of brocade,
hiding it within the patterns,
waiting for the right moment
to pass it on.
Unexpectedly,
he was assassinated and silenced
by people sent by Lai Luozhi.
But heaven's net is wide-meshed, yet lets nothing through.
The brocade with the second half of the prophecy
was coincidentally picked up by the illiterate Yuanniang,
who thought it was just good fabric.
She made it into the lining of a baby's shirt,
and so it was preserved.
[There is a triangular needle wound on Yuanniang's body]
If Yuanniang were just an ordinary woman,
how could she afford
such fabric?
This inner fabric
is certainly not something
that ordinary families could obtain.
The state preceptor is pedantic,
stubborn and obstinate.
Do we really want to hand over the country
to a foolish child
Or that useless Prince Xian?
Or the arrogant and domineering Princess Yong'an?
As long as Your Majesty
remain in court for one more day,
no one can feel at ease.
Once upon a time,
Princess Runing
was just as noble and revered.
Yet she was merely
framed by someone who switched the embroidery on her clothes,
and was accused of treason and usurpation,
leading to her current fate.
So,
Princess Runing
was also framed by your schemes.
If you hadn't been so suspicious,
how could I have succeeded so easily?
You have only yourself to blame.
You, Zhou Xu,
are the real threat to the Xiao imperial clan.
As a descendant of the Xiao family,
it is my duty to restore order to Cang State.
The throne rightfully belongs to me
by divine mandate.
I am the most legitimate heir to the throne.
But you are not the late emperor's son.
You are the child of the late emperor's favored concubine, Consort Shu,
born from her affair with another man.
Consort Shu was originally from the Nanlang State,
the carefree Princess Biluo.
[The child born from the illicit affair of the late emperor's favored concubine, Consort Shu, has vanished without a trace, and that child is Lai Luozhi.]
She fell in love with General Kongshan,
and they secretly pledged to marry.
It was meant to be a beautiful love story,
but her father, the King of Nanlang,
forced her to marry into Cang State with an imperial edict.
She was to be wed to the late emperor.
Princess Biluo swore she would rather die than comply.
In a fit of rage, the King of Nanlang
killed General Kongshan.
He further threatened the lives of the general's entire clan.
Biluo had no choice but to bribe the palace eunuchs
to escape the palace inspection.
She became known as
the infamous Consort Shu.
From then on,
she lost her love
and her name.
Her reason for living on
was not only to protect General Kongshan's clan,
but also for the sake of
the child of General Kongshan she carried in her womb.
This can't be true.
It's impossible.
My mother would never lie to me.
I am a descendant of the Xiao family.
I am the son of the late emperor of Cang State.
In the past, when Nanlang
escorted Princess Biluo to Cang State,
someone in the entourage
noticed that she was unwell
and discovered this matter.
Consequently, she secretly attempted to silence them.
Fortunately, this person managed to escape.
Lai Luozhi.
You are not of the Xiao bloodline at all.
Your entire life
is nothing but a complete lie.
Impossible.
My mother would never lie to me.
You mediocre rats,
you're all Zhou Xu's lapdogs.
You fabricate lies,
deceiving heaven and earth,
all to
prevent me from ascending to the throne
and saving the world.
Moths to a flame.
Born at dawn,
dead by dusk!
So,
moths flying to a flame
was all just a grand dream after all.
Open the door.
Yes.
Greetings, Guard Jing.
The Lai Faction has been brought to justice.
Grand Commander sent me here
to escort you home immediately.
Thank you for your hard work these past few days.
If the Imperial Security Bureau has been negligent in any way,
I ask for your forgiveness.
That's great!
Guard Jing,
you're too kind.
The Grand Commander
put us in the Imperial Security Bureau's prison,
which was actually to protect
us from harm by the Lai Faction.
How
could we not understand?
Yes, yes, yes.
[Cangming Hall]
Shen Du,
you must understand,
once the arrow is released from the bow,
there's no turning back.
I've made up my mind.
Madam Xu, please
inform Her Majesty.
Director Yan, please come back another day.
Her Majesty will
summon me shortly.
She has no time to see you now.
The officials of the Lai Faction
have all been ordered to be investigated.
What is the purpose of
meeting Her Majesty today?
I, as the Grand Commander, have pacified the rebels
and rendered great service to Cang State.
I'm asking Her Majesty for a reward.
Do I need to explain this
to a sixth-rank official?
Grand Commander Shen, then I must accompany you
to meet Her Majesty.
Suppressing the rebels wasn't your achievement alone.
I contributed as well.
This reward,
you can't have it all to yourself.
If you want a reward,
have your superior at the Ministry of Justice
submit a memorial.
Director Yan,
you may leave now.
Who asks for a reward
while bringing a gift themselves?
I suppose what's in this brocade box
is that evidence that shocked
the entire court, isn't it?
You're here today
for the Shen family, aren't you?
Director Yan,
watch your words.
We are now divorced.
You are no longer a member of the Shen family.
The affairs of my Shen family
are no longer your concern.
Fine.
Even if I'm not part of the Shen family anymore,
I will see this matter through to the end.
I stand here
not as
your wife,
but in my capacity as
the Director in the Ministry of Justice.
To reinvestigate wrongful convictions
and restore justice to the world.
This is my ideal.
Grand Commander Shen.
Her Majesty has summoned you inside.
Since you are an official in the Ministry of Justice,
you should be even more aware
Her Majesty has summoned
me, the Grand Commander.
How can you come uninvited?
Are you planning to barge into the hall?
If you go in alone,
then we need not meet again.
The Emperor has caught a cold.
Rest for a day,
and attend court tomorrow.
My beloved ministers,
is there any memorial to present?
Qiao Wenzhi,
you are in charge of Gannan Area.
Today,
is there any matter to report?
Your Majesty,
since Lai Faction was executed,
our Cang State has been prosperous with people living in peace,
especially Gannan Area, which is thriving,
truly, the world is at peace.
There is nothing to report.
You sound nice.
The Lai Faction has been executed,
but the ledgers he left behind
are very useful.
Qiao Wenzhi,
you've been smuggling goods from Xichen
through Gannan Area into Cang State for profit.
Your Majesty,
it's unjust!
The so-called evidence they left behind
by those rebels from Gannan Area
cannot be used as proof.
It's not credible!
Not credible?
Then,
how do you explain these two sets of books,
one true and one false?
These weren't submitted by the Lai Faction.
For the reconstruction of Ming Hall,
the real accounts and the fake ones,
differ by a full two times.
But the reconstruction of the Ming Hall
involved all departments.
It's not just me.
Qiao Wenzhi.
Stop talking nonsense!
Your Majesty.
Qiao Wenzhi
is an official under my command.
He was blinded by greed.
He embezzled the court's silver.
He committed a grave crime.
It's all my fault for not supervising properly.
I ask Your Majesty to punish me.
The fault of not supervising properly.
Prime Minister Zhang, you are truly knowledgeable.
Your choice of words is exquisite.
But this Qiao Wenzhi
is very loyal to you.
The majority of the embezzled funds
from the Ming Hall project
ended up in your pocket, Zhang Xingwei.
Zhang Xingwei.
Do you have anything else to say?
I
have nothing to say.
Prince Xian.
Mother.
Let me ask you.
How should we deal with him?
Mother, you are wise and decisive.
You have your own judgment.
I have my own judgment?
But I'm asking you now
what your judgement is.
I have been under Prime Minister Zhang's tutelage since childhood.
Prime Minister Zhang has always led by example
in educating me
to always prioritize the welfare of the state.
I don't believe
Prime Minister Zhang would commit such a crime
for mere silver.
This case
must have hidden circumstances.
Prince Xian,
you are so confused.
It was all my pretense.
I've deceived you for so many years.
Yet you still plead for me.
Well, well.
What a touching relationship between teacher and student.
Prime Minister Zhang,
let me speak on your behalf.
You obtained this silver,
but didn't spend any of it on yourself.
In the court,
you bribed allies
for the purpose of
inviting them to support Prince Xian together with you.
Your Majesty,
now that it has come to this,
I
will no longer conceal anything.
In this matter,
Prince Xian
truly knows nothing.
It was all done by me alone.
I request Your Majesty to grant me the death penalty
to serve as a warning to others.
You think sacrificing your life
will erase your sins
just like that?
Families that were destroyed because of you,
the loyal officials who died unjustly
can never be brought back to life.
Mr. Shen,
present it.
In accordance with heaven's will and the times,
received this clear mandate.
The guilty minister, Shen Bingzhu,
secretly communicated with the enemy,
[Shen's Mansion]
burned our military grain storage,
leaked our weapons blueprint,
colluded with foreign powers,
and betrayed his country.
His crimes deserve execution.
The entire Shen family shall be imprisoned and exiled.
Let it be known far and wide.
I don't seek fame in future generations,
only to remain true to my conscience
♫The clash of gold and iron shatters the world♫
and the common people.
♫Together, we advance and retreat side by side♫
My mentor, Shen Bingzhu, was naturally indifferent to worldly affairs.
♫The vast world stands proud, without regret♫
He never wanted to get involved in court disputes.
He only cared about the common people.
♫We stand firmly against the forces of evil♫
No matter who it is or what position they hold,
he only did what he thought was right,
♫In dreams, a hundred turns unfold♫
and all he wanted was for the people to be at peace.
I live off the emperor's salary,
♫Destiny binds us, walking together through life♫
so naturally, I should shoulder his burdens,
♫Unforgettable, the brief encounter♫
I'll do anything for His Majesty.
♫Like petals flying in the wind♫
♫Through thick and thin, unwavering in heart♫
♫I'll be with you forever♫
I, Shen Du,
♫At least I have you to share both joy and sorrow♫
now seek justice for my father
Shen Bingzhu.
♫Unravel fate, fearless and unyielding♫
I, Shen Du, son of the criminal minister Shen Bingzhu,
am here to denounce my father!
♫A dream brings me back♫
He colluds with foreign powers
♫The scenery is bright, hand in hand, we go back together♫
and aids the rebels!
I hereby denounce!
♫Through thick and thin, unwavering in heart♫
I, Shen Du, son of the criminal minister Shen Bingzhu,
♫I'll be with you forever♫
am here to denounce my father!
♫At least I have you to share both joy and sorrow♫
He colluds with foreign powers.
♫Unravel fate, fearless and unyielding♫
♫A dream brings me back♫
For my father Shen Bingzhu,
♫The scenery is bright, hand in hand, we go back together♫
Revenge
♫In this life, my heart remains untainted by dust or ash♫
Sixteen years ago,
our Cang State was at war with Xichen.
At a time when we urgently needed provisions,
the main granary storing our provisions
suddenly
caught fire in a mysterious blaze.
All of Cang State's provisions
were burned to ashes.
Shen Bingzhu, who was guarding the provisions,
was found to have private correspondence with the enemy
and was charged with a serious crime.
[Granary of Xiang'an, Cang State]
This grain sack
bearing the seal of the granary
from that year
should have been completely burned,
yet it appeared
in Gannan Area, thousands of miles away.
The letter of collusion with the enemy
that you handed to the late emperor
was discovered
to not have been written by Shen Bingzhu himself.
Prime Minister Zhang,
can you explain why this is?
When the war broke out that year,
my student came to me.
Only then did I learn
that he had colluded with local officials
to sell off the national granary's supplies.
They bought when prices were low
and sold when prices rose the following year,
profiting from the difference.
Unexpectedly,
the war with Xichen suddenly broke out.
The national granary's supplies
had already been sold off by them,
leaving only a pile of thatch.
Oh, Prime Minister Zhang,
I never imagined
that such a matter, capable of shaking the foundations of our Cang State,
would be connected to you.
Your Majesty,
I never imagined
that one day
I would commit
such an atrocious act
to cover up the crimes of my disciples.
It was I
who ordered someone to imitate Deputy Minister Shen's handwriting
and write that letter of treason.
You forged a letter of treason.
Then how did the fire
start?
Prime Minister Zhang,
do you want me to investigate further?
Your Majesty,
this is all my personal wrongdoing.
Let the death penalty stop with my family.
If you investigate further,
it will shake the foundation of our Cang State.
At that time,
you may be in a dilemma,
returning empty-handed,
and the losses will outweigh the gains, Your Majesty.
I may be in a dilemma?
What are you
refering to?
There are some things
I
cannot speak plainly.
Grand Commander Shen, please.
You trust me that much?
Aren't you afraid
that you and this brocade box might disappear together?
Over these years,
I have personally witnessed Your Majesty
working tirelessly for the welfare of Cang State's people.
I believe you will make
a fair decision.
I am willing
to stake my life on it.
Well,
I will speak plainly for you.
Before Deputy Minister Shen took over the granary,
the local official in charge
was my nephew,
Zhou Miao.
[Zhou Miao]
Fearing exposure,
he went so far as to collude with the Lai Faction,
using the Jinwu accelerant technique
to set our Cang State's granary
ablaze.
Your Majesty,
you...
Guards!
Take Zhou Miao out and interrogate him thoroughly.
All those involved from the Zhou family
will have their sentences increased by one degree.
Your Majesty, please spare my life!
Have mercy!
Prince Xian.
Let me ask you again,
how should Prime Minister Zhang
be dealt with?
I humbly request, Mother,
to deal with Zhang Xingwei according to the law.
However,
for the members of the Zhang clan,
I hope Mother will consider their past merits
and show leniency.